What you should aspire to do is every single thing that you administer or prescribe on
your program, just like a doctor prescribes medicine, they should know exactly why they're
prescribing it, where it is and amongst the, you know, periodization of what you're doing.
Like, there's no wasted motion.
It's like everything has a purpose and intent behind it.
And then you should understand the intent behind drills.
Some people see like a cone drill and they're just like, oh yeah, you got to cut.
You know what I mean?
But it's like, what are we focused on?
It's like, would you actually break down film?
You know, like, what does that cut actually look like?
Am I doing it under center of mass, outside center of mass?
If you change the leg position of where they're cutting 90 or 45 degrees, it completely changes
the demands of the leg.
If I'm under center of mass, I'm loading my hip.
If I'm outside, I require more ankle inversion, eversion stability across the knee.
So it's stuff like that for coaches to understand the intent behind the drill as opposed to
mindlessly doing it.